Once our clustering algorithm has identified clusters and prototype trajectories,
一旦我们的聚合算法识别了聚合以及原型轨迹
in this case three clusters with three prototype trajectories each,
在这个例子中是三个聚集以及三个原型轨迹
we can begin the job of online prediction for a vehicle that we meet on the road.
我们便可以开始为我们在路上碰到的车辆做在线预测工作了
First, we observed the vehicle's partial trajectory.
首先 我们观察该车的部分轨迹
Next we compare it to
接下来 我们将轨迹与
the corresponding segments of the prototype trajectories for each cluster.
每个聚合的原型轨迹的对应节作比较
This comparison is done using
这种比较是通过使用
the same similarity measure we used earlier to perform the clustering.
我们先前使用的同样的相似度测量来完成的
The belief for each cluster is updated based on
每个聚集对应的预期被更新
how similar the partial trajectory is to the prototype trajectories.
更新是基于部分轨迹和原型轨迹的相似性来完成的
And finally, we compute a predicted trajectory for each cluster.
最后 我们为每个聚集计算一个预测轨迹
For example, by taking the most similar prototype trajectory.
例如 将最相似的原型轨迹作为结果轨迹
Let's make this more clear by following this car forward
我们来更清楚地说明一下
in time from T equals zero to T equals one.
通过跟踪这辆车 从 T=0 时刻到 T=1 时刻
Let's go through these steps.
现在 我们来按照以上步骤操作一下
One, we observe the partial trajectory between time zero and one.
第一步 我们观察时间0和时间1之间的部分轨迹
It is this green line behind the vehicle.
也就是车辆后面的绿色线段
Two, well since all of the prototype trajectories overlap up to this point,
第二步 因为所有的原型轨迹在这一点互相叠加
the trajectory comparison step will yield the same probability for each cluster.
轨迹比较步骤将为每个聚合生成同样的几率大小
Three, even though there is no clear winner within each cluster we still have to choose
第三步 尽管当前并没有哪个原型轨迹好于其他轨迹
one prototype trajectory to represent each cluster and we
我们依然会选择一条原型轨迹来代表每个聚合
broadcast these three trajectories with their associated probabilities.
然后我们将这三条轨迹以及伴随的几率广播出去
Next, a T equal two- things get more interesting.
接下来 当 t=2 时候 事情开始变得有意思起来
First, let's get rid of the car so we can see the trajectory more clearly.
首先 让我们把车拿掉 这样我们能更清晰地观察轨迹
Now when you make a comparison of
现在 当我们把部分轨迹和
the partial trajectory with the nine prototype trajectories,
九条原型轨迹比较的时候
we find that the vehicle's partial trajectory
我们会发现这辆车的部分轨迹
seems more similar to the red than purple or blue.
与红色轨迹更加相似 而非紫色或者蓝色
When we update the associated probabilities we might get something like this.
当我们更新轨迹伴随的几率时 我们可能会得到类似这样的结果
Note that red grows in probability and the blue and purple both shrink,
请注意 红色轨迹的几率增加 而紫色和蓝色几率缩减
but blue shrinks more than purple since the partial trajectory is a worse match for blue.
蓝色缩减程度大于紫色 因为待测量轨迹和蓝色轨迹最不能匹配
Then, we pick the best prototype trajectory for
然后 我们为每个聚合选择最匹配的原型轨迹
each cluster and use them to represent the future trajectory of the car.
并使用它们来代表车辆的未来轨迹
As we continue this process,
当我们我们继续以上过程时
we see the probability for the red cluster quickly approaches one.
我们可以看到 红色聚合对应的可能性快速地接近值1